Guide to the Irma Tuck Weiss Papers 1954-1986 MC 211
New York University Archives
Irma Tuck-Weiss Papers
1954-1986
MC 211
New York University Archives
1.0 boxes
Irma Tuck Weiss was a professor of biochemistry at New York University from 1950-1978. From 1980-1981, she also served as the president of the College of Dentistry at New York University. Her main research topics included human saliva. This collection is comprised of her notes and research analyses.
1 linear foot
Tuck-Weiss, Irma.
Provenance
The papers were donated to New York University by the daughter of Dr. Irma Tuck-Weiss.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Irma Tuck-Weiss was born on August 5, 1913. She received her B.S. (1933), her M.A. (1936) and her Ph.D. from New York University.
Her notable academic appointments included Assistant Professor of Biochemistry (1950-1962), Associate Professor of Biochemistry (1962-1975), and Professor of Biochemistry (1975-1978). She was named professor emerita in 1978.
Her research on human saliva focused on standardizing and evaluating paper electropherograms of parotid saliva.
She served as President of the College of Dentistry in 1980. She was involved in some of extracurricular activities, as president of the Dental Chapter of the Research Scientific Society of America and the Omega Chapter of Omicron Kappa Upsilon in 1981, as well as an active participant in numerous student and fundraising activities.
She died on February 19, 2004 in New York. A scholarship was established in her honor.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains notes, paper electropherograms and writings by Dr. Irma Tuck-Weiss. The bulk of the collection documents Dr. Tuck-Weiss' professional life through correspondence, published articles, historical research, and information regarding her membership in various professional associations.
Arrangement
The files are grouped into one series.
New York University. College of Dentistry.; Biochemistry.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Electrophoresis.; Laboratory notebooks.; Photographs.; Research notes.
  - Antibacterial properties of saliva: Research and publications, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Antifungal research and analysis, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 1965-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class notes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and photographs, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Glycoprotein analysis, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Journals, bulletins and annoucements, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs and images, 1954-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Press clippings, 1959-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publications on human saliva, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Research, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Research, notes and publication, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Research, notes and results, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research on electrophoresis, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Research on electrophoresis, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Salivary indexing, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Salivary indexing, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Salivary indexing, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Salivaring indexing and notes, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Salivary indexing and notes, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Salivary indexing and notes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Salivary indexing, groups 4-6, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)